A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Log Files (Grant and Project Proposals) FA734
Rockefeller Archive Center
- 1987
  - L87-100: Southern Africa Development Council Committee: Support for training of SADCC representatives, 1987 (Reel L-522)
  - L87-101: University of Minnesota: Rural policy resources in Minnesota, 1987 (Reel L-522)
  - L87-105: American Academy of Arts and Sciences: Conference on scholarship exchange with Cuba, 1987 (Reel L-522)
  - L87-110: Cornell University: Fellowship support for students in International Agriculture Development, 1987 (Reel L-543)
  - L87-112: International Alliance for Sustainable Agriculture, Minneapolis, Minnesota: Information on alternatives to pesticide use in agriculture, 1987 (Reel L-543)
  - L87-115: Rand Corporation: Study of single teenage child bearing using high school and beyond, 1987 (Reel L-522)
  - L87-117: Committed Artists, South Africa: Further performing arts for disadvantaged South Africans, 1987 (Reel L-522)
  - L87-118: Chicago Reporter: Material development for program use, 1987 (Reel L-522)
  - L87-119: Operations Crossroads Africa, Inc., NY: Minority internships in International Development, 1987 (Reel L-522)
  - L87-122: Northern Illinois University: Politics in International Organizations, 1987 (Reel L-522)
  - L87-123: University of Witwatersrand: Resource education policy and curriculum for a post-apartheid South Africa, 1987 (Reel L-522)
  - L87-127: Montana Alliance for Progressive Policy: Study capital investment flows in the Montana State economy, 1987 (Reel L-522)
  - L87-132: Ford Foundation: Africa health and population initiatives, 1987 (Reel L-522)
  - L87-133: Ford Foundation: Community Development, 1987 (Reel L-534)
  - L87-139: San Diego State University: Documentary on Ralph Bunche, 1987 (Reel L-534)
  - L87-140: Committee for Human Rights in Cuba: To monitor human rights in Cuba, 1987 (Reel L-534)
  - L87-141: National Progressive Primary Health Care Committee, South Africa: Request for support to set up primary care network, 1987 (Reel L-534)
  - L87-146: Trinity Forum for International Security and Conflict Resolution: Support for Trinity Forum, 1987 (Reel L-543)
  - L87-147: Ford Foundation: Reception at Ford Foundation to celebrate publication of book: Corrective Capitalism: Rise of America's CDCs, 1987 (Reel L-534)
  - L87-148: Governor's Advisory Committee for Black Affairs: To advise the governor, State of New York, on various issues pertaining to minority populations, 1987 (Reel L-534)
  - L87-149: Ford Foundation: Political economy, 1987 (Reel L-573)
  - L87-151: Ford Foundation: Nairobi information log, 1987 (Reel L-534)
  - L87-153: Education Training: Resource Associates, Inc., Santa Cruz: National family life education network, 1987 (Reel L-534)
  - L87-154: Academy Council on U.N. System: General support, 1987 (Reel L-534)
  - L87-156: Institute for Research on Public Policy, Canada: MiddleTowers and the Trading System, 1987 (Reel L-534)
  - L87-157: University of Toronto: Labor Market Issues, 1987 (Reel L-534)
  - L87-159: The Freshwater Foundation, Minnesotta: Support for dissemination of publications on water issues, 1987 (Reel L-534)
  - L87-162: National Council of Negro Women, Inc.: Request funding of development educational project, 1987 (Reel L-534)
  - L87-163: Ford Foundation: For in-house use by fuel committee members who are Ford Foundation employees, 1987 (Reel L-534)
  - L87-166: National Institute of Building Sciences: Funding for their Rehab Task force, 1987 (Reel L-534)
  - L87-167: The Northside Preservation Commission: Horseshoe Area Development Project, 1987 (Reel L-534)
  - L87-171: Institute for Policy Studies: For December conference: Housing and Economic Development State/local and grassroots initiatives, 1987 (Reel L-534)
  - L87-174: The College for Human Services: Manifestation of service for the adult learner, 1987 (Reel L-534)
  - L87-175: Ford Foundation: International development projects, 1987 (Reel L-534)
  - L87-177: City of San Antonio: Two proposals: Enhancing fairness and equality; education in san Antonio, Texas, 1987 (Reel L-534)
  - L87-178: University of California (Berkeley): To establish commission on testing and public policy, 1987 (Reel L-543)
  - L87-180: The Wilderness Society: To analyze the economic impact of resource decisions on timber-dependent communities in the Pacific NorthWest, 1987 (Reel L-535)
  - L87-183: Metropolitan State University, St. Paul, Minnesotta: Incorporation of other colleges into their higher education curriculum program, 1987 (Reel L-557)
  - L87-184: Mennonite Economic Development Association, Canada: To improve the economic self-sufficiency and living conditions of cocoa farmers through the medium of an effective coop marketing system, 1987 (Reel L-535)
  - L87-185: Defense for Children International, Geneva, Switzerland and NY: Promotion and protection of Children's Rights, 1987 (Reel L-535)
  - L87-186: Sagewood Education Centre, South Africa: Non-racial education project in South Africa from the pre-school to secondary school levels, 1987 (Reel L-535)
  - L87-187: Atlantic Institute of International Affairs, Paris, France: General support, 1987 (Reel L-535)
  - L87-188: Asian Coalition of Human Rights Organizations (ACHRO), Manila: Potential project support out of Asia Regional Funds, 1987 (Reel L-535)
  - L87-189: Ford Foundation: Special project in community development, 1987 (Reel L-535)
  - L87-192: Oglala Lakota College: Re: Possible endowment for a continuing update and cataloging of (AIHEC) materials, American Indian Higher Education Consortium, 1987 (Reel L-535)
  - L87-193: University of Natal/Economic Resource Unit: To commission papers for publication and hold workshop to examine the relationships between South Africa and neighbors, 1987 (Reel L-535)
  - L87-194: Connecticut Women's Educational and Legal Fund Inc.: Support for cooperating attorneys program for litigation and resource project., 1987 (Reel L-551)
  - L87-195: Institute of International Education, Inc.: Church leader development program to expand educational opportunities for black South African clergy studying in the U.S., 1987 (Reel L-551)
  - L87-196: Clark University, Worcester, Mass: South African summer program and resource network in international development and social change, 1987 (Reel L-551)
  - L87-198: Federation of Community Centers of Alaska: Support for black women's leadership and economic development project, 1987 (Reel L-551)
  - L87-199: Sadat Peace Foundation Inc: economics of peacemaking in the Middle East, 1987 (Reel L-543)
  - L87-200: La-Coperativa: Study demographics, educational and socio-economic characteristics of recently legalized farm workers, 1987 (Reel L-535)
  - L87-204: Lighthouse Investment Group, Boston, Mass.: Expenses related to a black South African trade union project for consultation meeting in South Africa, 1987 (Reel L-543)
  - L87-205: University of Cape Town: Western Cape oral history project, 1987 (Reel L-535)
  - L87-206: National Federation of Community Development Credit Unions: Establish credit unions for rural areas, 1987 (Reel L-535)
  - L87-207: Kentucky Appalachian Foundation Inc.: Development of small businesses, 1987 (Reel L-536)
  - L87-208: Steven L. Camby: Research on arms control, 1987 (Reel L-543)
  - L87-211: Tacolcy economic Development Corporation, Inc.: PRI-for the redevelopment of land for Edison Center, 1987 (Reel L-536)
  - L87-214: Program for Appropriate Technology in Health: Request- grant and loan funds to establish a demonstration international program related investment plan to transfer health, nutrition, and contraceptive technology to the developing countries, 1987 (Reel L-536)
  - L87-215: The American Society of International Law: Publish international law, 1987 (Reel L-536)
  - L87-216: Ford Foundation: Ford Foundation: re: Social Science Initiative, 1987 (Reel L-536)
  - L87-217: National Youth Leadership Council, Maine: Indian Youth Leadership Project, 1987 (Reel L-536)
  - L87-221: Michigan State University: New models of in service training for teachers, 1987 (Reel L-536)
  - L87-222: Center for Women Policy Studies: National program on Math, Science,and Technology education for minority girls and women Building Bridges, 1987 (Reel L-536)
  - L87-227: St. Barnabas College: Core support of SBC outreach and the Southern African Association of Independent Schools, 1987 (Reel L-536)
  - L87-230: Community Based Educational Programme, South Africa: Meeting aspects of long and short term educational crisis in Black education, 1987 (Reel L-536)
  - L87-233: Tata Energy Resource Institute, India: Study of role of fuel wood and biomass energy in development, 1987 (Reel L-536)
  - L87-234: Order of Ethiopia: Proposal for Institute for Pastoral Education, 1987 (Reel L-537)
  - L87-235: Southern Methodist University School of Law: Project: Collaborative effort between Southern Methodist University Centre for Applied Legal Studies at the University at Witwatersrand, 1987 (Reel L-537)
  - L87-236: Foundation for Entrepreneurship Development: Possible fiscal year1988- grant action to a South African agency promoting small enterprise development among black South African women, 1987 (Reel L-537)
  - L87-241: Kwazulu Natal Indaba Foundation: For regional implementation analysis in Kwazulu and Natal, 1987 (Reel L-537)
  - L87-243: University of Natal: For curriculum development unit to undertake research training and community service activity, 1987 (Reel L-537)
  - L87-245: Former Members of Congress: Support for congregational study group on Germany, 1987 (Reel L-537)
  - L87-246: Die Suid-Afrikaan: Aid for trainee journalist on staff of Die Sud Afrikaan, 1987 (Reel L-537)
  - L87-247: Leadership Institute, South Africa: Training in management skills to the leaders of community organizations, 1987 (Reel L-543)
  - L87-250: Alliance for Justice: Support for lawyer solicitation program, 1987 (Reel L-537)
  - L87-251: Ford Foundation: Black Church file- significant issues, 1987 (Reel L-537)
  - L87-252: Ford Foundation: Support of more effective work by international organizations on problems related to environment and economic development, 1987 (Reel L-538)
  - L87-254: Ford Foundation: Program development, 1987 (Reel L-538)
  - L87-255: International Union for Conservation of Nature and Natural Resources (IUCN): General Support, 1987 (Reel L-538)
  - L87-256: National Research Center, South Africa: Center for research and information on matters affecting Black people, 1987 (Reel L-538)
  - L87-258: Opportunities Industrialization Centers International, Inc.: Development and instilization of technical skills training Centers in developing countries, 1987 (Reel L-538)
  - L87-259: Red para la infancia y la Familia, Costa Rica: Publication of bi-lingual bulletin and meeting in the field of infancy and the family, 1987 (Reel L-538)
  - L87-260: Pan American Development Foundation: For research and training on entrepreneurship for Latin American NGOs, 1987 (Reel L-538)
- 1988
  - L88-1: Ford Foundation: First round of proposal for FF competition in the Black Studies field, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-2: The Pennsylvania State University: Penn State Foreign Language Institute, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-3: Council of Large Public Housing Authorities: Public housing demonstration project, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-6: Ford Foundation: Minority teacher education, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-13: Natural Resources Defense Council, Inc.: Request for a PRI for purchasing and financing a permanent national headquarters, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-14: I.J. Markin Financial Services, Inc.: Rehabilitation of historic landmark Reliance Building in downtown Chicago, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-15: Remediation and Training Institute: Possible grant for remediation and training institute, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-16: Ford Foundation: Ford Foundation/Rural education, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-17: Center for Women's Economic Alternatives: Provide Educational support, resources and training to low-income rural women in North Carolina, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-21: Ford Foundation: Discussions of debt equity (Develop Country Loan Contribution program), 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-22: Learn and Teach, Johannesburg: Produces and Develops literacy materials and publications and trains literacy teachers in teaching literacy throughout South Africa, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-23: Ford Foundation: Discussions of future of non-consultative group for International. Agriculture Resource Centers, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-24: Inter-American Institute for Cooperation on Agriculture: For economic research in Latin America, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-25: Harvard University: Berlin Crisis, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-26: Harvard University: Program for Hungarian public officials, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-29: Council for Black Education and Resource: Training in job skills,education, and personal enrichment for Black community, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-30: Maryland University: Natural resource management. Training for low-income minority rural youth, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-36: University of Southern California: Workshops with the Institute of Strategic and International Studies, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-37: Asia-Pacific Institute for Broadcasting Development: Information Exchange for Women and Media in Asia and Pacific, 1988 (Reel L-557)
  - L88-39: University of Wisconsin: Parenting Intervention Program ( for AFDC mothers and their children), 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-40: California Coalition for Rural Housing project: To continue to spearhead a broad-based effort to confront an emerging housing crisis in California, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-41: Ohio State University Mershon Center: High school teacher training in national securities studies, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-42: University of Miami: Political economics. of U.S. - Latin America re: Drug trade, 1988 (Reel L-557)
  - L88-44: Coop Housing Foundation: For future PRI support, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-45: Brandeis University: For new undergraduate program in international studies, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-46: Caribbean Institute for Promotion of Human Rights: Research and publication of Educational and Human Rights issues in the Caribbean, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-47: International Center for Research on Women (ICRW): Five year program of expansion and collaboration, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-48: Ford Foundation: Conventional Arms Control, 1988 (Reel L-547)
  - L88-48: Ford Foundation: Conventional Arms Control, 1988 (Reel L-548)
  - L88-48: Ford Foundation: Conventional Arms Control, 1988 (Reel L-549)
  - L88-48: Ford Foundation: Conventional Arms Control, 1988 (Reel L-550)
  - L88-50: Far West Lab for Education Research and Development: Develop a training and technical assistance system for the caregiver of infants in the state of California, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-51: World Council of Credit Unions Inc.: Develop program that would document and research the role and impact that credit unions have in economic. development, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-53: Catherine McAuley Housing Foundation: To provide financial assistance to housing and community development activities, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-54: Washington Office on Latin America: Institutional support for WOLA, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-56: International Center for Research on Women (ICRW): Women's work health and child welfare in the Third World, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-58: Instituto Dominicano de Desarollo Integral, Inc.: For support for income-generating programs in Santo Domingo, 1958 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-59: Rayalaseema Seva Samithi: To organize women to enhance their learning potentials and enable them to exert greater control over their work environment, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-61: The Latin American Studies Association, Inc.: U.S.- Cuba dialogue and international relations, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-63: Minnesota Opera Company: For their new music ensemble, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-64: Jawaharlal Nehru University: World Congress on Human Rights, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-65: Barnes Early Childhood Center: A statewide evaluation of Minnesota ECFE and provide technical systems on program development and training, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-66: The National Learning Center: Developmentof a language enrichment model for disadvantaged children, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-68: United Nations Association of the United States of America, Inc.: Staff and program restructuring, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-71: Berea College: Support for proposed Brushy Fork Institute to alleviate poverty in Appalachia, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-72: University of California at Davis: Study relationships between irrigation, development and social economic conditions in rural communities, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-73: University of Minnesota (Dept. of Agriculture and Applied Economics): Funding for book on aid and development, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-75: University of Florida- Institute of Food and Agricultural Sciences: Project to investigate the role of entrepreneurs in rural economic development, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-76: University of Denver College of Law/ Transportation Law College: Comprehensive study on the deleterious impact of transportation deregulation on economics of rural areas, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-77: Ceip Fund Inc.: Identify minority professionals interested in Natural Resource Management and Scholarships, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-78: Instituto Centro Americano de Administracion de Empresas, Costa Rica: Training courses in Management of Natural Resources in Central America, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-81: Ford Foundation: Drug abuse, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-83: BIDCO Finance Joint Venture: Michigan strategic fund for establishment minority BIDCO, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-84: Consortium for Language Teaching and Learning: Project support, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-88: Brown University- Right and Reason: For Rights and Reason, Brown University black theatre project dedicated to the process of scholarly research leading to dramatic expression, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-90: Institute for International Economies: Trade policy cooperation among the IMF/World Bank/ and the GATT, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-92: Ford Foundation: Small business, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-93: Christian-Appalachian Project, Kentucky: Attach the root causes of poverty while helping people to help themselves, 1988 (Reel L-545)
  - L88-94: Kentucky Highlands Investment Corporation: Job training and venture development program for Central Appalachian region, 1988 (Reel L-546)
  - L88-95: Ford Foundation: Immigration (material in this file brought forward to L92-9), 1988 (Reel L-546)
  - L88-96: Ford Foundation: Minority public policy pipeline, 1988 (Reel L-546)
  - L88-97: University of London: Research political violence: its causes and implications, 1988 (Reel L-546)
  - L88-99: University of North Carolina: Replication of NYC Housing and vacancy survey database, 1988 (Reel L-546)
  - L88-100: Programa LatinoAmericano de Actividades en Poblacion, Buenos Aires: Population activities, 1988 (Reel L-546)
  - L88-103: City University of New York: Updating a history of Black politics in South Africa, 1988 (Reel L-546)
  - L88-106: Association for Asian Studies, Inc.: Distribution of back issues of the Journal of Asia Studies, 1988 (Reel L-546)
  - L88-107: Ford Foundation: Middle school math demonstration project, 1988 (Reel L-546)
  - L88-108: American Jewish World Services, Inc.: Develop and test prospect structures for the temporary storage of grain, 1988 (Reel L-546)
  - L88-109: Memorial University of Newfoundland: Aid for FOGO Process communications techniques in promoting participatory development in development, 1988 (Reel L-546)
  - L88-110: International Food Policy Research Institute: Study of policy against poverty in developing countries, 1988 (Reel L-546)
  - L88-111: Instituto Inter-Ameircano de Corporacion para la Agricultura: Conduct studies of macro economic policy impacts on rural poor in Latin America, 1988 (Reel L-546)
  - L88-112: Centro Latino Americano de Demographica, Chile: Integrate demographic variables into development planning, 1988 (Reel L-546)
  - L88-113: Tomas Rivera Center: For recruitment and retention of teachers who can meet the needs of minority children not proficient in English, 1988 (Reel L-546)
  - L88-114: Tucker County Development Authority, Parsons, W.VA: Economic development, 1988 (Reel L-546)
  - L88-115: University of West Indies: Social works program, 1988 (Reel L-557)
  - L88-116: Institute for Defense and Disarmament Studies: Support for World Weapon Database, 1988 (Reel L-546)
  - L88-117: ICWI Group Foundation, Inc.: Development of local Philanthropy in Jamaica, 1988 (Reel L-546)
  - L88-120: Georgia State University: Pending proposal for preparation of a book on Social Support and Parenting in Low-Income Families, 1988 (Reel L-546)
  - L88-121: Catholics for a Free Choice: CFFC/voice in favor of enlightened population policies and family planning services, 1988 (Reel L-557)
  - L88-125: American G.I. Forum: Redevelopment of American G.I. forum, 1988 (Reel L-546)
  - L88-133: Beacon Fund: Achieve higher rate of control appreciation than normally realized from investments in public equity markets by making venture capital investments in lieu and expanding human service companies which offer possibility of long-term growth, 1988 (Reel L-546)
  - L88-138: Ford Foundation: Community development consultants, 1988 (Reel L-546)
  - L88-139: National Training and Information Center: For NTIC's housing conference, Initiatives for Affordable Housing and agenda for 1980's, 1988 (Reel L-546)
  - L88-142: West Indies University of Norman Manley Law School and Legal Aid Clinic: Legal service, 1988 (Reel L-575)
  - L88-144: University of Maryland Foundation: Support Sudanese political science in U.S. foreign policy making program at University of Maryland School of Public Affairs, 1988 (Reel L-544)
  - L88-146: International Institute for Strategic Studies (IISS): Funding for Military Balance 1987-88, 1988 (Reel L-546)
  - L88-147: University of Maryland Foundation: Support Chinese senior researcher at University of Maryland School of Public Affairs, 1988 (Reel L-544)
  - L88-148: University of Maryland: To strengthen BA/MPM Afro-American studies program, 1988 (Reel L-546)
  - L88-150: West Virginia Scholars Academy: Training opportunities for rural minority candidates, 1988 (Reel L-546)
  - L88-151: University of Delaware: Study to analyze land use and environmental planning systems, 1988 (Reel L-546)
  - L88-152: Cultural Survival, Inc.: Funds for forestry project to minimize social conflict and maximize popular participation in conservation and resource management, 1988 (Reel L-546)
  - L88-153: Ford Foundation: Middle East Research Competition, 1988 (Reel L-546)
  - L88-154: Cornell University: Research on Irrigation Water Decision Making, 1988 (Reel L-546)
  - L88-157: Women's Global Network on Reproductive Rights, Amsterdam: For women's advocacy groups and providers of reproductive health services worldwide, 1988 (Reel L-544)
  - L88-158: National Law Income Housing Preservation Commission: Funding for affordable housing center, 1988 (Reel L-544)
  - L88-159: American Institute for Learning, Texas: PRI to finance the purchase of a new building to house American Institute for Learning initiatives and programs, 1988 (Reel L-544)
  - L88-160: National Housing Partnership: Promote the development and preservation of low-income housing, 1988 (Reel L-544)
  - L88-162: Ford Foundation: American law Schools (See PA89-250), 1988 (Reel L-544)
  - L88-164: Regional Plan Association, NY: Project on global economic activities, 1988 (Reel L-544)